Wenbo Guo

(+86) 13258285996 | honywen@stu.scu.edu.cn | github.com/lxyeternal | about.honywen.com

ABOUT

A master's graduate at the School of Cyberspace Security of Sichuan University. My research interests are vulnerability detection and software supply chain security. Related achievements are published in JIFS, C&S journals and ASE, RAID conferences. My supervisors are Prof. Yong Fang and Prof. Cheng Huang. I will continue my research in cybersecurity in the future.

EDUCATION

Sichuan University

Chengdu, China

M.E. in Cybersecurity, GPA3.82/4 (2/92)

Sept. 2020 - Jun. 2023

Sichuan University

Chengdu, China

B.E. in Cybersecurity, GPA: 3.54/4(Top 10%)

Sept. 2016 - Jun. 2020

Research Experience

Postgraduate Research Assistant

Aug. 2022 – Current

Nanyang Technological University (advisor: Prof. Yang Liu)

School of Computer Science and Engineering

- Made a large-scale empirical study of the PyPI ecosystem.(ASE 2023)
- Proposed a novel detection tool for PyPI malicious packages.

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Jun. 2018 – Jun. 2020

Sichuan University

School Of Cyber Science And Engineering

- Discovered illegal activities and key hackers in underground forums.
- Proposed a key hacker identification algorithm named HackerRank.
- Built a threat intelligence analysis system named ThreatMiner for hacker forums.

PROJECTS

Vulnerability mining system for C/C++ source code | Graph Neural Networks

Aug. 2021 – Aug. 2022

- Built a database of CVE vulnerabilities of open source software.
- Proposed pruning method with code structure supplementation.
- Proposed a fused graph neural network vulnerability detection method.
- Found some unpublished vulnerabilities.

Digital Currency Fraud Website Detection System | Machine Learning, Flask

Oct. 2020 – Mar. 2021

- Constructed a feature matrix unique to digital currency fraud sites.
- Proposed a machine learning based detection model.
- Developed a digital currency fraud website detection system.

PyVul: Python code vulnerability mining system | Deep Learning, OVO SVMs

Sept. 2019 – Apr. 2021

- Proposed a pruning method for python code snippets.
- Proposed a vulnerability mining method that combines code detection and contextual analysis.
- Found some vulnerable code snippets in StackOverflow.

A threat intelligence analysis system for hacker forums | Deep Learning, Flask May. 2019 - May. 2020

- Tracked and collected data from multiple underground forums, e.g. 0x00sec, Nulled, HiddenAnswers.
- Proposed a key hacker identification algorithm that integrates text analysis and social network analysis.
- Proposed an effective method to build a hacker profile with multiple dimensions.
- Developed a threat intelligence analysis system for hackerforums.

A QR Code Logistics Privacy Systeml | Android, RSA, Mysql

Jun. 2018 - Mar. 2019

- Design of segmented encryption and authorization mechanisms based on the principle of least privilege.
- Obfuscation of QR codes using logstics chaos algorithm.
- Developed a express Android APP with privacy protection.

Publications

- Wenbo Guo, Zhengzi Xu, Chengwei Liu, et al. An Empirical Study of Malicious Code In PyPI Ecosystem[C]. ASE 2023 (Accepted).
- Wenbo Guo, Yong Fang, Haoran Ou, et al. HyVulDect: A Hybrid Semantic Vulnerability Mining System Based on Graph Neural Network[J]. Computer & Security, 2022, 121: 102823, doi: 10.1016/j.cose.2022.102823.
- Haoran Ou, Yong Fang, Wenbo Guo, et al. Viopolicy-Detector: An Automated Approach to Detecting GDPR Compliance Violations in Websites[C]. RAID, 2022.
- Wenbo Guo, Cheng Huang*, Weina Niu, et al. Intelligent mining vulnerabilities in python code snippets[J]. Journal of Intelligent & Fuzzy Systems, 2021, 41(2): 3615-3628. doi: 10.3233/JIFS-211011.
- Cheng Huang, Wenbo Guo, Yongyan Guo*, et al. HackerRank: identifying key hackers in underground forums[J]. International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks, 2021. doi: 10.1177/15501477211015145.
- Haoran Ou, Yongyan Guo, Chaoyi Huang, Zhiying Zhao, **Wenbo Guo**, et al. No Pie in The Sky: The Digital Currency Fraud Website Detection[C]. ICDF2C, 2022: 176-193. doi: 10.1007/978-3-031-06365-7_11.
- Liang Liu, Wenbo Guo*, Yuwei Yang, Huaiyu Guo. Research on QR code logistics privacy based on segmented encryption and time-limited control[J]. Chinese Journal of Network and Information Security, 2019, 5(4): 63-70.

AWARDS AND HONORS

• Provincial Excellent Graduates of Sichuan Province	Mar. 2023
• First-class Academic Scholarship	Oct. 2022
• Sichuan University OPPO-CTF Competition Winner	May. 2022
• Dahua Scholarship	Dec. 2021
• Outstanding Student Cadre	Oct. 2021
• National Encouragement scholarship	Dec. 2019
• First Prize of Sichuan University "Internet +" Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition	Oct. 2019
• Second Prize of the National Student Cybersecurity Training Camp	Sept. 2019
• Second Prize of the 12th National Student Information Security Competition	Aug. 2019
• Third Prize of the 4th Shanghai Student Cybersecurity Competition	Nov. 2018

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: C/C++, Java, Android, Python, MySQL, HTML/CSS

Frameworks: Flask, TensorFlow, Pytorch, Keras, DGL Developer Tools: Linux, Git, Docker, PyCharm, Latex

Languages: Chinese, English(IELTS: 7(Overall))